KURT STATHAM

SUMMARY

A 12-year veteran of the casual game industry in search of my next challenge. Extensive QA and site production experience. Adept at multitasking with a keen desire to apply new skills and concepts. Strong communication, collaboration, problem-solving and analytical skills.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Java, HTML, CSS, Shell Scripting FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: React, Node.js, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize OTHER TECH: Mac, Linux, Windows, Outlook, Excel, Word, Git, SVN, Jira, Confluence, Command Line

EMPLOYMENT

DEFY Media, Director, Site Production, Los Angeles, CA

Apr. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- Managed all scheduling and production for the Addicting Games and Shockwave websites.
- Reviewed and approved all prospective Shockwave site content.
- Requested and coordinated the addition of additional features to both the customer facing sites and back end services.
- Served as the technical liaison between the site production and engineering teams.
- Successfully built and maintained relationships with a variety of content providers.
- Identified and remedied any production-related site issues, improving customer experience.
- Trained and mentored junior staff.

Nickelodeon/DEFY Media, Game Release Engineer, Los Angeles, CA

July 2011 - Mar. 2017

- Produced and tested games for the Addicting Games and Shockwave websites.
- Authored content for Shockwave's most popular game, "The Daily Jigsaw".
- Maintained and improved legacy production systems.
- Wrote scripts to automate and streamline game production.
- Assisted in transitioning sites to new ownership.
- Coordinated content delivery for dozens of daily titles ensuring minimal service disruption.

Nickelodeon, Games Tester, San Francisco, CA

June 2008 - June 2011

- Manually tested 4-5 games per week to uncover functional and gameplay issues.
- Identified and remedied online game and site issues.
- Verification of bug fixes/regression testing.
- Tested new site features and functionality.
- Ensured a consistent user experience across all titles.

Nickelodeon, Assistant Manager, Customer Support, San Francisco, CA

Apr. 2007 - May 2008

- Assisted customers with technical issues and billing inquiries.
- Supervised and trained junior staff.
- Organized and oversaw team projects.
- Managed department during supervisor's medical leave.

EDUCATION

UCLA Extension

Certificate Full Stack Web Development 2019

City College of San Francisco

Certificate Java Programming 2010

University of California, Berkeley

B.A. French 2003